Guide to the Terry Tempest Williams Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Papers chiefly after 2002, 1940s-2011 bulk: 2002-2011
  - Photographs
    - Photographs, negatives, slides, notes, some family materials, circa 1990-1998, 2002 (Box 311)
    - "National Wildlife Refuges 2000 Calendar"; photograph of Williams, 1993, 1993, 2000 (Box 312 (Oversize))
    - Family portrait photograph, 2002 (Box Broadside 313)
    - Photographs of Terry Tempest Williams and Flo Krall Shepherd, 2003 (Box Broadside 314)
    - Photograph album, circa 2003 (Box 315 (Oversize))
  - Printed Materials
    - Denver Rocky Mountain News, January 2000; printed materials on prairie animals, 1986-2000 (Box 316)
    - Bosch calendars, photocopy, 1996-2000 (Box 317 (Oversize))
    - Posters, "Watershed: Writings, Nature, and Community", "Haskell-Baker Wetlands", "Prairie Dogs", 1996, 2001 (Box Broadside 318)
    - America's Red Rock Wilderness Act of 1999, matted (Box Broadside 319)
    - Posters by Anita Thacher and Cathey Billian, with text by Williams, 2000 (Box Broadside 320)
    - Posters, photographs, printed material, circa 2000-2002 (Box 321 (Oversize))
    - Lecture posters, 2000-2003 (Box 322 (Oversize))
    - "Tell the Truth" poster, University of Utah Alumna Award, Bosch print and news article, 2000-2007 (Box 323 (Oversize))
    - Posters, circa 2000-2005 (Box 323a (Oversize))
    - Newspapers, magazines, writings, circa 2001 (Box 324)
    - Newspapers, circa 2001, 2008, 2010 (Box 325)
    - Magazines, writings, correspondence, clippings, circa 2001-2007 (Box 326)
    - Lecture posters, printed materials, "Above the Fruited Plain" page proofs, photographs, awards, watercolor, circa 2002-2008 (Box 327 (Oversize))
    - Melstone Montana artist book by Rosie Hughes, calendars, magazines, newspapers, sketch, bird egg print, prints by Davis Te Selle, circa 2003-2009 (Box 328 (Oversize))
    - New York Times advertisement, "Whatever It Takes: Battle for the Heart of America" by Rick Bass, 2004 August 31 (Box Broadside 329)
    - New York Times advertisement, "Engagement: The Open Space of Democracy" by Terry Tempest Williams, 2004 September 2 (Box Broadside 330)
    - Poster, painting, envelope, 2004, 2011 (Box 331 (Oversize))
    - Newspapers, flyers, photocopies, circa 2004-2007 (Box 332 (Oversize))
    - Newspapers from Obama's inauguration, awards, posters, newsletters, circa 2006-2008 (Box 333 (Oversize))
    - Book cover "Still", printed material, circa 2007 (Box 334 (Oversize))
  - Awards
    - Utah State University commencement material, newspaper, magazine, circa 1999-2001 (Box 336)
    - Terry Tempest Williams honorary degree recipient portrait, circa 1999-2001 (Box 337 (Oversize))
    - Utah Center for the Book Award photographs, posters, awards, photographs, "Open Space of Democracy" page proofs, circa 2000-2003 (Box 338 (Oversize))
    - Photographs, University of Utah photo and honorary degree album, red Sanibel and Captiva Islands bag, sea shell, pen, circa 2003 (Box 339 (Oversize))
    - Award, 2003 (Box 340 (Oversize))
    - Award, 2004 (Box 341 (Oversize))
    - "The Illuminated Dessert" cover proofs, posters, Wilderness Society Award, 2006-2010 (Box 342 (Oversize))
    - Awards, undated (Box 343 (Oversize))
  - Artwork and Objects
    - Collage box, sea shells, photos, notebook given as a gift, circa 2001-2010 (Box 344)
    - Tile mosaic by Williams, "Detail: S. Apollinare Nuovo, Ravenna, 2002, Italia" (Box 345 (Oversize))
    - Palm leaf crown from FGCU fiasco, dried jelly fish with letter and photograph from Mama, circa 2004 (Box 346 (Oversize))
    - African textile artwork (Box Broadside 347)
    - Feather, shell, seeds (Box 348 (Oversize))
    - Flower petals, animal vertebrae (Box 349)
    - Necklace, frog brooch, slide viewer (Box 350)
    - Sea shells and feather (Box 351)
    - Rolodexes (Box 352)
    - Sea shells (Box 353)
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Audiovisual materials, including VHS and audio cassettes (Box 354)
    - Audiovisual materials, including 2 micro-cassette recorders with tapes, 20 VHS cassettes, and 33 audio cassettes (Box 355)
    - Audiovisual materials, including VHS and audio cassettes (Box 356)
  - Restricted Papers
    Restricted until January 1, 2037. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
    - Restricted correspondence (Box 360)
    - Restricted correspondence (Box 361)
    - Journals, circa 1990-2011 (Box 361)
- March 2013 Acquisition, 0.21; (1 box)
  - Notes for a talk at the Beinecke Library on Rachel Carson's notebook, 2013 March 28 (Box 363)